<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DJ.00935">
   
   
   <teiHeader>
      
      <fileDesc>
         
         <titleStmt>
            
            <title>Birds of Nebraska</title>
            
            <author>James E. Ducey</author>
         
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            
            <publisher>UNL Libraries Electronic Text Center
</publisher>
            
            <pubPlace/>
            
            
            
            <availability status="unknown">
               
               <p>Publicly accessible</p>
               
               <p n="public">URL: http://libr.unl.edu:2000/</p>
            
            </availability>
            
            <date>© 2003 </date>
         
         <idno/></publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc><bibl><title level="a">A Very Sensible Bird [Ovenbird].</title><title level="j">Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title><author>Editor [possibly Greenleaf].</author><date>1917-06-24</date><biblScope>52(39): 4-E. A bird editorial.</biblScope></bibl></sourceDesc>
      
      </fileDesc>
   
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body><div>
         
         <head>A Very Sensible Bird.</head>
         
         <p>If you don't mind ruthless frightfulness on the part of the Missouri Valley mosquito squadron now infesting our most delightful wooded spots, you might try a jaunt through the Fontenelle Reserve or the forests north of Florence today, and make yourself acquainted with a very sensible bird.</p>
         
         <p>He is the Golden Crowned Thrush, better known as the Ovenbird, and has a well earned reputation as being a favorite often heard but seldom seen. The man who sees an Ovenbird is likely to have a reputation among amateur ornithologists such as is borne by the sea-faring party who is constantly sighting sea-serpents.</p>
         
         <p>For the Ovenbird is of a modest and retiring disposition - very. He attends to his affairs in the deepest clumps of undergrowth in dark ravines, as a general thing, and doesn't mix very much with his more demonstrative neighbors.</p>
         
         <p>His name is secured from the shape of his nest, which is built of grasses on the ground, a fair imitation of a miniature oven. During this season the shape of this nest isn't the only way in which it resembles an oven, either. Admiral Peary wouldn't feel a bit at home in those deep-cut ravines, where no cooling breeze can filter.</p>
         
         <p>But the Ovenbird shows his wisdom by constantly seeking knowledge. His cry is "Teacher! Teacher! Teacher!" with the accent on the last syllable. It is a call never mistaken after once heard.</p>
         
         <p>Fontenelle Reserve is well populated with Ovenbirds. They will be glad to see you, albeit you will be lucky if you succeed in seeing them.</p>
         
         <cit>
            
            <bibl default="false">Editor [possibly Miles Greenleaf]. June 24, 1917. A Very Sensible Bird [Ovenbird]. <title>Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title> 52(39): 4-E. A bird editorial.</bibl>
         
         </cit>
      
      </div></body>
   
   </text>

</TEI>