<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI.2 id="DJ.00178">
   
   
   <teiHeader type="text" status="new">
      
      <fileDesc>
         
         <titleStmt>
            
            <title>Birds of Nebraska</title>
            
            <author>James E. Ducey</author>
         
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            
            <publisher>UNL Libraries Electronic Text Center
</publisher>
            
            <pubPlace/>
            
            <idno/>
            
            <availability status="unknown">
               
               <p>Publicly accessible</p>
               
               <p n="public">URL: http://libr.unl.edu:2000/</p>
            
            </availability>
            
            <date>© 2003 </date>
         
         </publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc><bibl><title level="a">Cleanly Birds of Winter.</title><title level="j">Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title><author>Editor [possibly Greenleaf].</author><date>1921-12-25</date><biblScope>57(13): 12-E. A bird editorial.</biblScope></bibl></sourceDesc>
      
      </fileDesc>
   
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         
         <head>Cleanly Birds of Winter.</head>
         
         <p>Every bird that stays with us during the winter months engages in frequent baths - not as frequently as in summer, but a lot more so than most humans during the Jack Frost era. It is remarkable that wild things of the feathered tribes should be so cleanly - but they are.</p>
         
         <p>While humans are comfortably shivering in all sorts of wraps and mittens, the Goldfinches and Siskins and Chickadees and Nuthatches - and all of the many other winter residents in birdland - blithely seek an open spot in the ice for lave themselves withal. When they come forth from these baths they are glorious indeed!</p>
         
         <p>Every amateur ornithologist knows that the Goldfinch - better recognized as the Wild Canary - changes his brilliant winter garb for more modest sparrow-like wear in the winter. Yet, when Goldfinch takes his bath and properly preens himself, much of his July glory is to be recognized in December.</p>
         
         <p>This is also true of the Pine Finch, or Siskin - first cousin of the Goldfinch, that occasionally comes down to us from Canada in the winter to add to the joy of a hike through the woods. After Siskin has taken his or her bath in the ice water of the purling creek - how those feathers glisten with the chrome and orange otherwise disguised!</p>
         
         <p>White Breasted Nuthatches, newly purged in the pool of ice fringe, come forth blue as Bluebirds and fool us when we look eagerly into the barren tangle of branches. Red-breasted Nuthatches bathe their ruddy little bosoms in the tinkling stream and brazenly display them in the sunshine with the rufous loveliness of Venus set in the brick-red of Nebraska sunset. Vivacious Chickadees, like flappers, dolled for the occasion, come from the ice water to shake a wicked chin at us, and to flirt most criminally!</p>
         
         <p>Ah, human-kind - what is there of us that our Birds do not know and do&gt;
</p>
         
         <p>What is there of loveliness and appreciation, dear Omnipotent, that you have failed to give the birds?</p>
         
         <p>In the life of these winter songsters of ours there is no Saturday night - as far as baths are concerned - for they bathe when we shudder at the very thought.</p>
         
         <p>In their dear lives they smile at us - and so many of us do no see that smile!</p>
         
         <p>They talk to us ad sing to us and sympathize and criticize - and they keep themselves always clean - like Bird Scouts, perhaps - "physically strong, mentally awake and morally straight."</p>
         
         <cit>
            
            <bibl default="NO">Editor [possibly Miles Greenleaf]. December 25, 1921. <title>Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title> 57(13): 12-E. A bird editorial.</bibl>
         
         </cit>
      
      </body>
   
   </text>

</TEI.2>