<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DJ.00117">
   
   
   <teiHeader>
      
      <fileDesc>
         
         <titleStmt>
            
            <title>Birds of Nebraska</title>
            
            <author>James E. Ducey</author>
         
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            
            <publisher>UNL Libraries Electronic Text Center
</publisher>
            
            <pubPlace/>
            
            
            
            <availability status="unknown">
               
               <p>Publicly accessible</p>
               
               <p n="public">URL: http://libr.unl.edu:2000/</p>
            
            </availability>
            
            <date>© 2003 </date>
         
         <idno/></publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc><bibl><title level="a">Blown From the Rockies.</title><title level="j">Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title><author>Editor [possibly Greenleaf].</author><date>1919-01-12</date><biblScope>54(15): 4-E. A bird editorial.</biblScope></bibl></sourceDesc>
      
      </fileDesc>
   
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body><div>
         
         <head>Blown From the Rockies.</head>
         
         <p>Mostly because of the infinite variety of features furnished by nature to the observer is the study of birdlife so engrossing, for this study is, of necessity, in the big outdoors, which is in itself intimate.</p>
         
         <p>Every "hike" the bird-lover takes through the fields and woods, winter or summer, spring or fall, storming or clear brings at least one new idea to make that tramp worth while.</p>
         
         <p>As an example of the strange freaks that sometimes occur in birdland we might mention the arrival in Omaha last week of the Green Tailed Towhee.</p>
         
         <p>To the reader uninterested in bird life this statement doesn't mean much, but to even the casual student it is a sensation.</p>
         
         <p>The Green Tailed Towhee is a sort of cousin of the Chewink or Towhee so well known to every rambler in the summer woods of these parts, but the Green Tail holds forth only from the western slopes of the Rockies to the Pacific ocean, and up and down the Pacific slope. That it should be found in Omaha would seem, on the face of it, preposterous.</p>
         
         <p>Yet a specimen of this beautiful species was found, dead, in the snow along "Billy" Marsh's winter shack on Carter lake, only last week. The poor little thing had evidently got off the trail and wandered down into these unfriendly parts just at the time when the mercury was far below zero. Thus he met an untimely demise.</p>
         
         <p>There is no point to these remarks except that there is always something interesting and new to be found in one's rambles. This, we think, is the first Green Tailed Towhee ever identified in Nebraska.</p>
         
         <cit>
            
            <bibl default="false">Editor [possibly Miles Greenleaf]. January 12, 1919. <title>Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title> 54(15): 4-E. A bird editorial.</bibl>
         
         </cit>
      
      </div></body>
   
   </text>

</TEI>