<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DJ.00329">
   
   
   <teiHeader>
      
      <fileDesc>
         
         <titleStmt>
            
            <title>Birds of Nebraska</title>
            
            <author>James E. Ducey</author>
         
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            
            <publisher>UNL Libraries Electronic Text Center
</publisher>
            
            <pubPlace/>
            
            
            
            <availability status="unknown">
               
               <p>Publicly accessible</p>
               
               <p n="public">URL: http://libr.unl.edu:2000/</p>
            
            </availability>
            
            <date>© 2003 </date>
         
         <idno/></publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc><bibl><title level="a">From Nebraska.</title><title level="j">Oologist</title><author>Dworak, Anton.</author><date>1887-03-01</date><biblScope>4(2): 84.</biblScope></bibl></sourceDesc>
      
      </fileDesc>
   
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body><div>
         
         <head>From Nebraska.</head>
         
         <list type="simple">
            
            <item>Editor <title>Oologist</title>:</item>
         
         </list>
         
         <p>Reading the descriptions of collecting trips in the <title>Oologist</title> reminds me of the "best day" I have ever had. It was in the season of 1885, which, by the way, is the year in which I became interested in oölogy, when I decided to go on a collecting trip. As there is no one in Geneva besides myself interested in oölogy I went alone. In order to reach the river where I meant to go, I had to cross a large prairie farm, just the place to collect, so of course I commenced hunting for nests of the Prairie hens and Killdeers. I had been tramping around awhile and had found three sets of Killdeer's (one set had two eggs and the others three each) when I was startled by a loud whirr,and looking down saw within three feet of me a nest of the Prairie Hen. You can easily see how elated I felt. Well, I passed on trying to find more but did not until I came to the river; there of course I found plenty of such as Blue Jays, Catbirds, Thrush etc., etc., and was beginning to despair of finding anything rare, when I looked up and saw-well, I felt like "yelling right out"-for it was the nest of a Great Horned Owl. But there was one difficulty. I had just got a new pair of climbers, and did not know how to use them as well as I do now; but finally I got up and got the eggs-three-down safely. After hunting around a while longer I started home, richer by many specimens than I had been in the morning.</p>
         
         <list type="simple">
            
            <item>Anton Dworak,</item>
            
            <item>Geneva, Neb.</item>
         
         </list>
         
         <cit>
            
            <bibl default="false">March-May 1887. <title>Oologist</title> 4(2): 84.</bibl>
         
         </cit>
      
      </div></body>
   
   </text>

</TEI>