<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI.2 id="DJ.00742">
   
   
   <teiHeader type="text" status="new">
      
      <fileDesc>
         
         <titleStmt>
            
            <title>Birds of Nebraska</title>
            
            <author>James E. Ducey</author>
         
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            
            <publisher>UNL Libraries Electronic Text Center
</publisher>
            
            <pubPlace/>
            
            <idno/>
            
            <availability status="unknown">
               
               <p>Publicly accessible</p>
               
               <p n="public">URL: http://libr.unl.edu:2000/</p>
            
            </availability>
            
            <date>© 2003 </date>
         
         </publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc><bibl><title level="a">Robin Red Breast Spring Harbinger. Groh Interviews the Cheerful Fellow, Who is Perched in a Cherry Tree. Wife to Come Back Later.</title><title level="j">Omaha Morning Bee</title><author>Groh, A.R.</author><date>1917-02-13</date><biblScope>46(205): 9.</biblScope></bibl></sourceDesc>
      
      </fileDesc>
   
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         
         <head>Robin Red Breast Spring Harbinger</head>
         
         <head>Groh Interviews the Cheerful Fellow, Who is Perched in a Cherry Tree.</head>
         
         <head>Wife to Come Back Later</head>
         
         <head>By A.R. Groh.</head>
         
         <p>Whom do you think I saw yesterday?</p>
         
         <p>Robin Red Breast, harbinger of spring. yes, sir.</p>
         
         <p>He was busy, harbingering spring with all his might in our back yard. He was in a cherry tree. I walked slowly in his direction. He cocked a curious eye at me.</p>
         
         <p>"Welcome, home, dear Red Breast," I said.</p>
         
         <p>"Thank you kindly, sir," he replied, "but I fear  came a little early. That warm day or two fooled me."</p>
         
         <p>"You can't come too early to suit us," I said.</p>
         
         <p>"Thank you," he said, "but you must remember that our nests aren't steam heated and the frozen ground makes our feet numb. That's why I'm sitting in the tree."</p>
         
         <head>Gathers Up Crumbs.</head>
         
         <p>"What in the world do you live on at this time of year?" I asked.</p>
         
         <p>"Well," said Robin, "we would be in a tight place if it weren't for the Audubon society people and other friends, who throw crumbs out for us. For myself, I'd rather have a nice fat angle worm any day than the best bread on earth. But I'll manage to get along on this till the worms begin to appear.</p>
         
         <p>"I was looking over the old nest and, I'm afraid wife and I will have to build a new one. Wind and rain and show have about done for the old one."</p>
         
         <p>He looked up in a maple tree at the fluttering remnants of last year's nest.</p>
         
         <p>"Do you mean to tell me you find your way back to the very same nest every year?" i cried in astonishment.</p>
         
         <p>Robin smiled.</p>
         
         <head>Finds Old Nest.</head>
         
         <p>"Why, certainly," he said.</p>
         
         <p>"But how can you?" I said. "Even a person couldn't do that?"</p>
         
         <p>"Ah, we can do many things that persons can't do," he said. "My winter home is in a larch tree in the yard of a home near Birmingham, Ala. Wife is still down there. She'll be up in a few days. Her health isn't any too good. I just came ahead to have a look at the nest and get things ready."</p>
         
         <p>"Just a minute and I'll get you some crumbs," I said.</p>
         
         <head>Prefers Bugs.</head>
         
         <p>"These crumbs are very good," said Robin. "Still, as I remarked before, I look forward to the good old worms and bugs."</p>
         
         <p>"Well, just so you let our cherries alone, you can have all the worms and bugs you want," I declared.</p>
         
         <p>Robin looked back.</p>
         
         <p>"I didn't think that of you, sir," he said. "I took a few last year, just a very few. But after I had eaten about a thousand bugs and worms I felt you wouldn't mind if I took a cherry or two just as a sort of dessert. However, If you - "</p>
         
         <p>"Dear Robin," I cried, "you just take all the cherries you want and welcome. Having your cheerful presence here is worth all the cherries on the tree."</p>
         
         <cit>
            
            <bibl default="NO">February 13, 1917. <title>Omaha Morning Bee</title> 46(205): 9.</bibl>
         
         </cit>
      
      </body>
   
   </text>

</TEI.2>