<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DJ.00310">
   
   
   <teiHeader>
      
      <fileDesc>
         
         <titleStmt>
            
            <title>Birds of Nebraska</title>
            
            <author>James E. Ducey</author>
         
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            
            <publisher>UNL Libraries Electronic Text Center
</publisher>
            
            <pubPlace/>
            
            
            
            <availability status="unknown">
               
               <p>Publicly accessible</p>
               
               <p n="public">URL: http://libr.unl.edu:2000/</p>
            
            </availability>
            
            <date>© 2003 </date>
         
         <idno/></publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc><bibl><title level="a">The First Meadowlark.</title><title level="j">Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title><author>Editor [possibly Greenleaf].</author><date>1920-02-29</date><biblScope>55(22): 10-E. A bird editorial.</biblScope></bibl></sourceDesc>
      
      </fileDesc>
   
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body><div>
         
         <head>The First Meadowlark.</head>
         
         <p>Everyone, nearly, hankers for the season just ahead. Snow looks fine from July, and new potatoes are alluring from December. So now we anxiously await the advent of spring, and all signs thereof are eagerly welcomed.</p>
         
         <p>The First Robin is an exploded theory as far as weather prognostication is concerned. The Bluebirds are a little better, because they are very seldom seen in as large numbers as this winter. But the tout ensemble of the bird census in this vicinity during the past couple of months has been calculated to encourage us in the hope of early violets.</p>
         
         <p>What seems to be the most impressive suggestion that the Ground Hog was right when he failed to see his shadow on February 2, is the fact that there are so many different sorts of spring birds already in the field, and that the Horned Larks are nesting before the first of March.</p>
         
         <p>Not only have a considerable number of harris Sparrows been seen during the past two weeks, but numerous Meadowlarks have been reported. "Strays" of the latter species are occasionally espied, here and there over the southern part of the state, every winter, but they are unusually frequent this season.</p>
         
         <p>The Harris Sparrow is rarely seen in the Omaha district before the last part of March - but have been identified many times this February.</p>
         
         <p>If the birds are right - including the first Meadowlark - perhaps we are really to have the blessing of an early and balmy spring, which will not cause much grief among our citizens.</p>
         
         <cit>
            
            <bibl default="false">Editor [possibly Miles Greenleaf]. February 29, 1920. <title>Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title> 55(22): 10-E. A bird editorial.</bibl>
         
         </cit>
      
      </div></body>
   
   </text>

</TEI>