<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DJ.00622">
   
   
   <teiHeader>
      
      <fileDesc>
         
         <titleStmt>
            
            <title>Birds of Nebraska</title>
            
            <author>James E. Ducey</author>
         
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            
            <publisher>UNL Libraries Electronic Text Center
</publisher>
            
            <pubPlace/>
            
            
            
            <availability status="unknown">
               
               <p>Publicly accessible</p>
               
               <p n="public">URL: http://libr.unl.edu:2000/</p>
            
            </availability>
            
            <date>© 2003 </date>
         
         <idno/></publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc><bibl><title level="a">The Red-breasted Nuthatch.</title><title level="j">Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title><author>Editor [possibly Greenleaf].</author><date>1918-10-06</date><biblScope>54(1): 4-E. A bird editorial.</biblScope></bibl></sourceDesc>
      
      </fileDesc>
   
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body><div>
         
         <head>The Red-breasted Nuthatch.</head>
         
         <p>There is nothing more entrancing to the bird-lover than the possibility of new discoveries. The man who likes to hike generally ends up with a naturalistic hobby of some sort - either the study of birds, flowers, insects or trees - for he can keep himself the best of company with such amateur research.</p>
         
         <p>So the discovery of something new in his particular line makes him pant with impatience for each day o which he can regale himself in the outdoors. No prospective bridegroom ever eyed the calendar more ardently than the new ornithologist awaiting "der tag."</p>
         
         <p>Thus it is good to know that there is every indication that this is to be a big winter in birdland.</p>
         
         <p>For the lover of the feathered tribes, seasons vary. In the winter of 1916-17, for instance, there were vast flocks of Redpolls, Crossbills and Red-breasted Nuthatches in the vicinity of Omaha. There are very temperamental critters, and appear as they listeth - here today and gone tomorrow. Just how cranky they can be is evidenced by the fact that only two pairs of Crossbills were seen in Omaha in the winter of 1917-1918, and no Redpolls or Red-breasted Nuthatches at all!</p>
         
         <p>But the Red-breasted Nuthatch has already been seen on the western outskirts of the city, and this, the Audubons would fain to believe, is indicative that more will follow, and that the outdoor sportsman with his nature glasses is to have a grand old season.</p>
         
         <p>We hope it is so. There is nothing more interesting than the study of birds, especially when the birds decide to help us with their presence.</p>
         
         <p>There is no war in the woods. Peace reigns supreme, and there is the place for you to be today.</p>
         
         <cit>
            
            <bibl default="false">Editor [possibly Miles Greenleaf]. October 6, 1918. <title>Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title> 54(1): 4-E. A bird editorial.</bibl>
         
         </cit>
      
      </div></body>
   
   </text>

</TEI>