<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DJ.00296">
   
   
   <teiHeader>
      
      <fileDesc>
         
         <titleStmt>
            
            <title>Birds of Nebraska</title>
            
            <author>James E. Ducey</author>
         
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            
            <publisher>UNL Libraries Electronic Text Center
</publisher>
            
            <pubPlace/>
            
            
            
            <availability status="unknown">
               
               <p>Publicly accessible</p>
               
               <p n="public">URL: http://libr.unl.edu:2000/</p>
            
            </availability>
            
            <date>© 2003 </date>
         
         <idno/></publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc><bibl><title level="a">Feathered Picnickers [Grackle and Jay].</title><title level="j">Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title><author>Editor [possibly Greenleaf].</author><date>1919-08-10</date><biblScope>54(45): 10-E. A bird editorial. Feathered Picnicker column repeats 19 Sep 1926.</biblScope></bibl></sourceDesc>
      
      </fileDesc>
   
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body><div>
         
         <head>Feathered Picnickers.</head>
         
         <p>Around every picnic ground in every park there will be found, with the usual exception that is noted in all pets, a couple of the most suave and obliging birds of picnic prey in the business - the Bronzed Grackle and the Blue Jay.</p>
         
         <p>These birds are large and powerful, as well as having appetites commensurate with their size. They have the brains of a burglar and would much rather secure their food for nothing than pay for it with hard work. SO they follow the camps of the picnickers.</p>
         
         <p>It is no uncommon sight in our larger and more popular parks to see whole flocks of Grackles stalking or fluttering somewhat sedately about the premises waiting for a chance to clean up after the merrymakers. The Blue Jays, while not so numerous, are equally crafty and equally eager.</p>
         
         <p>A Grackle can fly away with a ham sandwich as easily as you would carry it in your pocket, while the Jays are just as strong but a little more inclined to nefarious theft. They will sneak up on the victuals when nobody is looking and attempt to massacre a bunch of fried chicken already deceased.</p>
         
         <p>In any park it is a common sight to see a Bronzed Grackle, sometimes known as the Crown Blackbird, flying away with what would seem to be at least half a loaf of bread, with which to feed its young.</p>
         
         <p>During the winter the Blue Jay hangs around places where food is spread, such as the menagerie in Riverview park, but the Grackle takes no chances and goes south.</p>
         
         <p>No picnic is complete without these camp-followers. They are useful birds, since they are out-door house-cleaners. The Grackle has no bad habits, but the Jays occasionally tear up other birds' nests and eat their eggs.</p>
         
         <cit>
            
            <bibl default="false">Editor [possibly Miles Greenleaf]. August 10, 1919. Feathered Picnickers [Grackle and Jay]. <title>Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title> 54(45): 10-E. A bird editorial. Feathered Picnicker column repeats 19 Sep 1926.</bibl>
         
         </cit>
      
      </div></body>
   
   </text>

</TEI>