<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DJ.00671">
   
   
   <teiHeader>
      
      <fileDesc>
         
         <titleStmt>
            
            <title>Birds of Nebraska</title>
            
            <author>James E. Ducey</author>
         
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            
            <publisher>UNL Libraries Electronic Text Center
</publisher>
            
            <pubPlace/>
            
            
            
            <availability status="unknown">
               
               <p>Publicly accessible</p>
               
               <p n="public">URL: http://libr.unl.edu:2000/</p>
            
            </availability>
            
            <date>© 2003 </date>
         
         <idno/></publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc><bibl><title level="a">Phoebe and Towhee.</title><title level="j">Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title><author>Editor [possibly Greenleaf].</author><date>1918-03-31</date><biblScope>53(26): 4-E. A bird editorial.</biblScope></bibl></sourceDesc>
      
      </fileDesc>
   
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body><div>
         
         <head>Phoebe and Towhee.</head>
         
         <p>The sounds of spring are no less pronounced, joyous and welcome than its other loveliness. While the emerald glory of the woods and fields faintly suggests itself and the odor of the mellow earth and sprouting vegetation delights the dilated nostrils, there comes the first chirrup of the summer songsters to complete the promise of Nature's fulfillment.</p>
         
         <p>With the Bluebirds and Robins among us for several weeks, the arrival of the Phoebe and the Towhee seems to relegate winter far enough into the forgotten past to make those sub-zero months a part of a dismal nightmare.</p>
         
         <p>The old bridge over the creek is embellished now by the presence of Mr. and Mrs. Phoebe, who will shortly nest among the beams beneath it, and woe betide the insects that shall fly the air in that vicinity! The sharp emphatic exclamation "Phee-be!" is heard near each of these structures and soon the dainty bird itself is seen perched nearby, on the lookout for his flying food.</p>
         
         <p>And there is the Towhee, of Chewink - sometimes known as the Ground Robin - scratching about in the underbrush like some pretty little hen. The resounding "Cherink!" of this handsome bird reminds one of green vegetables and baseball games - for it is a spring song in the highest.</p>
         
         <p>It is a lot of fun to keep track of the march of the seasons as measured by the birds, and you can little afford to miss these glorious weeks.</p>
         
         <p>Each Sunday hike will afford new wonders, of which you should take immediate advantage.</p>
         
         <p>Oh, by the way! Have you seen the Waxwings? The woods are full of 'em and they are very companionable. Perhaps they are disappointed that you have not called.</p>
         
         <cit>
            
            <bibl default="false">Editor [possibly Miles Greenleaf]. March 31, 1918.  <title>Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title> 53(26): 4-E. A bird editorial.</bibl>
         
         </cit>
      
      </div></body>
   
   </text>

</TEI>