<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DJ.00391">
   
   
   <teiHeader>
      
      <fileDesc>
         
         <titleStmt>
            
            <title>Birds of Nebraska</title>
            
            <author>James E. Ducey</author>
         
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            
            <publisher>UNL Libraries Electronic Text Center
</publisher>
            
            <pubPlace/>
            
            
            
            <availability status="unknown">
               
               <p>Publicly accessible</p>
               
               <p n="public">URL: http://libr.unl.edu:2000/</p>
            
            </availability>
            
            <date>© 2003 </date>
         
         <idno/></publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc><bibl><title level="a">Harris's Woodpecker in Nebraska.</title><title level="j">Oologist</title><author>Reed, M.H.</author><date>1890-02-01</date><biblScope>7(2):29.</biblScope></bibl></sourceDesc>
      
      </fileDesc>

<revisionDesc><change when="2006-05-10"><name>Vicki Martin</name> Proofread from Source</change></revisionDesc>


   
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body><div>
         
         <head>Harris's Woodpecker in Nebraska.</head>
         
         <p>Along the latter part of December, I was walking through a strip of timber about one-half mile west of town, when right in front of me, I head the rapping of some Woodpecker. I walked nearer as silently as possible, when a Flicker flew up and away. I walked on more rapidly, then thinking that was all there was, when out jumped what I thought at first sight, was a Downy Woodpecker. It lit on a stump about ten yards ahead of me and I could see it plainly. It was much to large for a Downy and I thought to dark for a Hairy. I watched it for almost an hour. It came quite near me several times, but flew away almost as soon as it saw me.</p>
         
         <p>At last the mate (a male I think) came up and I saw them no more that day.</p>
         
         <p>I went home not knowing what I had seen.</p>
         
         <p>The following Thursday a traveling-man, who is quite a "bird crank," came around and I took him out. As soon as he laid eyes on my bird he said, "Boy, that's a Harris's Woodpecker." Well I was glad to hear that, for several of our local sages (?) had declared that I had only seen a Downy or perhaps a Hairy Woodpecker.</p>
         
         <p>M. H. Reed,<lb/>Otoe Co., Neb.</p>
         
         <cit>
            
            <bibl default="false">February 1890. <title>Oologist</title> 7(2):29.</bibl>
         
         </cit>
      
      </div></body>
   
   </text>

</TEI>