<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DJ.00465">
   
   
   <teiHeader>
      
      <fileDesc>
         
         <titleStmt>
            
            <title>Birds of Nebraska</title>
            
            <author>James E. Ducey</author>
         
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            
            <publisher>UNL Libraries Electronic Text Center
</publisher>
            
            <pubPlace/>
            
            
            
            <availability status="unknown">
               
               <p>Publicly accessible</p>
               
               <p n="public">URL: http://libr.unl.edu:2000/</p>
            
            </availability>
            
            <date>© 2003 </date>
         
         <idno/></publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc><bibl><title level="a">Jenny [House Wren].</title><title level="j">Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title><author>Editor [possibly Greenleaf].</author><date>1918-06-16</date><biblScope>53(37): 4-E. A bird editorial.</biblScope></bibl></sourceDesc>
      
      </fileDesc>
   
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body><div>
         
         <head>Jenny.</head>
         
         <p>Although we have spoken of her before, Jenny Wren deserves an additional tribute.</p>
         
         <p>There are mornings when the war news isn't quite as good as we would like to have it - but Jenny, with her indomitable spunk, furnishes instant cheer and a splendid example.</p>
         
         <p>Nothing feazes the House Wren - which is Jenny's real name.</p>
         
         <p>Storms, physical combat, personal grief, anxiety of any sort has positively no effect on her good nature, nor on her vocal efforts.</p>
         
         <p>As far as belligerency is concerned, she reminds one a good deal of Belgium. She will fly into the enemy English Sparrows with a fearlessness and fervor that can't help but call forth the plaudits of the multitude - and she wins most of such battles, too. Woe betide the "winged rat" that perches in front of Jenny's house, like a miniature dog-in-the-manger! Mrs. Wren makes short work of him.</p>
         
         <p>But her song - that incessant, delicious bubble of encouragement, for all the world like the rippling of a fresh, cool brook - that is what endears the House Wren to everyone!</p>
         
         <p>Ever on the alert in the capture of insects and worms which might wreck the war garden, Jenny mixes work and pleasure, and has a song for every chapter in her daily life.</p>
         
         <p>We could take an excellent lesson from Jenny House Wren - especially during these parlous times!</p>
         
         <cit>
            
            <bibl default="false">Editor [possibly Miles Greenleaf]. June 16, 1918. Jenny [House Wren]. <title>Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title> 53(37): 4-E. A bird editorial.</bibl>
         
         </cit>
      
      </div></body>
   
   </text>

</TEI>