<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DJ.00162">
   
   
   <teiHeader>
      
      <fileDesc>
         
         <titleStmt>
            
            <title>Birds of Nebraska</title>
            
            <author>James E. Ducey</author>
         
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            
            <publisher>UNL Libraries Electronic Text Center
</publisher>
            
            <pubPlace/>
            
            
            
            <availability status="unknown">
               
               <p>Publicly accessible</p>
               
               <p n="public">URL: http://libr.unl.edu:2000/</p>
            
            </availability>
            
            <date>© 2003 </date>
         
         <idno/></publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc><bibl><title level="a">Cherink! Cherink [Towhee]!</title><title level="j">Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title><author>Editor [possibly Greenleaf].</author><date>1922-04-02</date><biblScope>57(24=27): 8-E. A bird editorial.</biblScope></bibl></sourceDesc>
      
      </fileDesc>
   
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body><div>
         
         <head>Cherink! Cherink!</head>
         
         <p>To those of us who delight in tramping the woodland and the tangled ravines in both winter and summer, the first remarks of the retiring Towhee come as a springtime kiss - a sort of salute by Mother Nature, who is good to her own!</p>
         
         <p>He has many songs and carols, which develop as his amorous ardor increases, but he announces his return to the thickets which we prowl, with the single ejaculation - </p>
         
         <p>"Cherink!"</p>
         
         <p>This clinking, grating, undescribable observation on the part of Brer Towhee is a masterpiece of God's outdoor handiwork. It comes to us who "hike" as a remark from heaven itself.</p>
         
         <p>It has none of the louder and more apparent choral beauties of the efforts of the Robin and the Bluebird - nor of the chattering year-around insistency of the Chickadee - but it chinks to us from forbidden messes of weeds and bushes, to say that spring has really arrived, and that somewhere, in a ground-nest hidden beneath some fallen twig of leaf-cluster - there is to be a large family of "Ground-Robins" born.</p>
         
         <p>Presently these Towhees will cease their "Cherink" and will perch on a branch above that mysterious hard-to-find nest, and warble "See-Towhee!" with exasperating loveliness - while the lowly, sneaking Cowbird seeks the Chewink nest that humans seldom strike.</p>
         
         <p>Blessed is this bird indeed! Beautiful, songful and mysterious. Protect it.</p>
         
         <p>"Cherink!"</p>
         
         <cit>
            
            <bibl default="false">Editor [possibly Miles Greenleaf]. April 2, 1922. Cherink! Cherink [Towhee]! <title>Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title> 57(24=27): 8-E. A bird editorial.</bibl>
         
         </cit>
      
      </div></body>
   
   </text>

</TEI>