<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DJ.00082">
   
   
   <teiHeader>
      
      <fileDesc>
         
         <titleStmt>
            
            <title>Birds of Nebraska</title>
            
            <author>James E. Ducey</author>
         
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            
            <publisher>UNL Libraries Electronic Text Center
</publisher>
            
            <pubPlace/>
            
            
            
            <availability status="unknown">
               
               <p>Publicly accessible</p>
               
               <p n="public">URL: http://libr.unl.edu:2000/</p>
            
            </availability>
            
            <date>© 2003 </date>
         
         <idno/></publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc><bibl><title level="a">Birds About Broken Bow.</title><title level="j">Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title><author>Morgan, Frances C.</author><date>1922-11-26</date><biblScope>58(9): 3-W.</biblScope></bibl></sourceDesc>
      
      </fileDesc>
   
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body><div>
         
         <head>Birds About Broken Bow.</head>
         
         <p>Broken Bow, Nebraska, November 12. - My Dear Mr. Griswold: When in your city, several weeks ago, I called twice to see you, but failed to find you in the office either time. I wanted to have a little chat with you on "birdlore," as there are so many things I wanted to learn direct from you about this wonderful subject. Both Mr. Morgan and myself thoroughly enjoy your articles in the World-Herald each week, and read with a great deal of interest your wonderful stories about our little feathered friends and their habits. You certainly know birds. Only wish I had the time and opportunity for more of this wonderful study.</p>
         
         <p>I note what you say in today's paper about the summer birds having left your vicinity so early, and all going at once, in one night, as it were. This was not the case here, until the end of October, and then left us in a cloud. The Robins were with us yesterday, as I counted forty-five around the bird dishes on the lawn, but expect they have gone now, as we have had a windy snow-storm all last night and today, and I am afraid I have seen the last of my little companions until another season. The Flickers are with us, for I saw one this morning traveling the tree trunks in quest of food, and yesterday I saw a Downy hunting in the crevices of the bark for a sweet morsel to eat. We have any number of Chickadees, Brown Creepers and Pine Siskins, also. Last year the Brown Thrasher and the Catbird stayed here until the second week in October, which was unusually late for these birds, was it not?</p>
         
         <p>We had a pair of catbirds that raised two broods in the same nest this year, in the clematis vine on our coal shed, within three feet of the door that was used two and three times a day. I know the Brown Thrasher will return to the same nest the second season, but is it not a very unusual thing for the Catbird to do so, and especially to raise the two broods the same summer, and in the very same nest?</p>
         
         <p>We had a new bird this last summer, that is an Oriole I know, and yet can find no description of it in any book on birds that I have. Others have noted it and phoned to me about it. It is slightly larger than the Baltimore and has the same colorings, only more white in the wing, and the breast has more of a reddish yellow, and quite different from the Baltimore. Such a strikingly brilliant bird, and beyond my powers of description. We saw it all summer, and it would come and bathe with the other birds, but was very shy. Its song is like the Baltimore, only a few more notes added to the scale. I know the Orchard Oriole well, and it is nothing like that. We have had the Ovenbird here for the past two years. Every season adds a new friend to our already fun list, for this part of the country. I believe the two whose coming I long for most eagerly are the American Redstart and the Wren. I forgot to add that we have any number of slate colored juncos with us and they have been here for a month at least. After reading your article a little while ago, I had to write and tell you of the birds that are with us right now. Yours truly. Frances C. Morgan.</p>
         
         <cit>
            
            <bibl default="false">November 26, 1922. <title>Omaha Sunday World-Herald</title> 58(9): 3-W.</bibl>
         
         </cit>
      
      </div></body>
   
   </text>

</TEI>